Which is the cheapest and most useful health insurance in India?
That means that once a hospital case comes up, the
money shouldn't be taken away from us
.
We need to get the best facility.  Once the claim has been received, don't just
say "I'm sorry" and then
deny the claim.  It really doesn't even take five minutes to figure this out
.  The first thing to understand is that not the
same
company or plan is best for everyone.   If
that's the case, why don't you tell me the company and plan I took?
Why did we
compare so many companies to find out which one is the best for each person? That's why the
best company changes according to our age, according to our illnesses, according to the district we live in, according to the features we need.
So today we are going to find the
best plan or company for each of us or each family. It's a
little different from the videos we made before, and it's
detailed, but
I will tell you that today so that everyone can understand. Many families are destroyed by
illnesses. If it's a minor
illness, it's in the tens of thousands,
but if it's a big accident like
cancer, heart disease, liver disease, kidney
problem,
we have to sell everything we have and hate it. How
much better is it to take out
insurance for a very small amount of money? We
see a lot of messages on Vap, saying that we should help this family, and they have sold
everything they have and borrowed from those who can afford it, and then
when they get into a situation where they can't get the loan, many people
send us such messages via WhatsApp,
but they don't have a picture of their own family.  No
one leaves a message without anything,
so to prevent this situation from
happening to anyone else, we need to find
a good health insurance plan as soon as possible and
take it immediately.
You should also share this video with them. This is
a video that only those with good financial responsibility are likely to see. It is
very difficult for this video to reach the common man without us sending it.
So
share the video now. Let's find the
most useful health insurance
plan that suits us today. Whether we take health insurance
through an agent, through companies, or
through aggregator platforms, the policy is issued to us by the
respective insurance companies.
So no matter which way we take, there is no problem.
However,
I am giving a link in the description and comment
box where you can compare about 51 companies on a single screen with an online discount of up to 25 percent. If you are an expatriate, in
addition to this online discount of up to 25 percent, an 18% GST waiver is also
available. So, taking the plan of the company that
we find most suitable for us
or that we are interested in will be the
most profitable. Now,
let's compare and find the best plan.
For that, if you
check the link given in the comment, it will look like this  There will be an
interface where you can see
who is taking it for,
their age, our pin code, do
we have any diseases, etc.
We just have to select and leave things honestly.
We can see various plans of different companies on a single screen.
Now, if we like more than one company,
select each of them and hit the compare option.
We can easily read the features column by column.
Then, it doesn't even take five minutes.
We can quickly take a plan of our choice. If you
look here, we can also see the EMI facility. If you still have
doubts,
we have the option of call back in Malayalam.
Apart from that, here you can see an option for a representative to
come to your house and explain all the plans.
But I'm saying that none of this is
necessary. Now, if you pay attention to what I'm going to say,
we can find a health insurance on our own.
Because every
day we are late, we are at a greater risk
because we don't know how big this disease is going to be or whether
any accidents are going to happen to us.
So,
we should take a health insurance in advance. If
we look at this screen,
we will see many plans.
300 400  Plans with coverage of up to one crore rupees per month are
available here.
We can also take plans from the best companies in India.
But cheap or low-priced is
not the same as cheap. If we can easily state our criteria
while taking a health insurance, then an
insurance of one rupee
has a coverage of 10 lakhs.  Meanwhile,
another insurance policy worth Rs 8,000 also
has a coverage of Rs 10 lakh.  The claim
settlement ratio for both companies is approximately the
same.  So
why would people be interested in taking out
insurance for Rs 8,000?  Because
2000 rupees per year is profitable.  But these two
insurance policies were taken out by two different people
.  Both of them are facing
a claim of Rs. 10 lakh.  It is at this point that
he realizes that cheap or inexpensive insurance lacks features
.  Maybe
there's a room rent limit, maybe
there's a clause that says "copay."  Otherwise,
consumables will no longer be covered.
When all this is added up,
the insurance company will probably only pay three or four lakh rupees for a bill of 10 lakhs
.  This is not a
scam by the insurance company,
they must have already mentioned that cheap insurance only has that one feature
.
He
took out this insurance for Rs 8,000 without reading this and just looking at the price.  Meanwhile, the
other
insurance has all these features for a difference of just Rs. 2,000
.  At that time, when
a claim for Rs. 10 lakh came, he
received only Rs. 10 lakh.  If
not, then I received Rs. 9 lakh 90,000
.  The remaining 10,000 rupees was
probably spent on food or something else that wasn't covered
.  Even then, for a
difference of Rs 2,000, the person who took out the
best insurance would have made a profit of almost Rs 6 lakh
.  So,
realize that cheap is never our criterion. Low price should not be the only
criterion. Make sure that it
covers all the features we need. If you
pay attention to the things that are going to be said next, you will
easily understand what things should be in a good insurance policy and how to find the best company by combining all of them. The second is
network hospital and cashless
treatment. That is, there will be
hospitals that are affiliated with an insurance company. If the hospitals are included in
their network hospital
list, we can get the service in such
hospitals without cash and once we
take out the policy, we can get the
service.  We
go to a hospital, we give our insurance card
or insurance PDF
or that insurance number to the
hospital's insurance help desk, and
when we are admitted, they don't
charge us a single penny.
Completed matters will be
settled between the insurance company and the hospital
.  If we get a bill for 10 lakhs,
we first
pay 10 lakhs and then
submit the entire bill to the insurance companies and get
it back. This is called
reimbursement. It is
unlikely that someone will suddenly take 10 lakhs.
Therefore, cashless is the best. So
how do we know if the hospitals we want are
cashless? If we
go and take a cheap policy,
maybe the hospitals we want are not
cashless. Then, as
shown in this screen, there is an option to
check the cashless hospital list of the insurance company that we like while reading the features. If we
click on it, we will see the lists of
hospitals in the vicinity of our house
.  Check carefully to see if there is a list of premium hospitals that we
regularly go to or that we would
like to go to
.  Don't you remember that we
initially gave the location or zip code? The
list of cashless hospitals is
shown here based on the zip code given.  Otherwise, if we
take an insurance company's network hospital, there will be
many hospitals,
tens of thousands of hospitals.   It's
hard to figure out from that whether it's near our house.  But
because technology is used here, we
were shown which hospitals in our area would offer cashless payment based on our zip code.  So,
first of all, we look and see that
the hospitals we need near our homes do
n't have cashless payment.  So what we need
to understand is that this insurance policy is
not suitable for us.  Sometimes it might
suit someone else
because the hospitals they go to
are cashless and have good features
.  It has good features,
but the hospitals we go to are
not cashless.  So this doesn't suit us, let's
look at the second one.
So, while we are looking at two or three companies,
we are naturally
able to find insurance companies that offer cashless facilities at the best hospitals near our homes.  Now, how much coverage is
needed is an important issue.
Many times, insurance provided by companies or government-provided insurance does not
benefit people.
This is because there is not enough
coverage. It is generally
said that if it is a child, then
each of them should have a minimum coverage of Rs. 10 lakh. If they are
older, but not yet 50 years old, then they should
have a coverage of at least Rs. 10 lakh. If they are
above 50 years of age, then a
coverage of Rs. 15 lakh is preferable. But
when looking at this, the premium is high. If there is a
situation where I cannot afford it, we should think about it like
we eat food and
wear clothes. Health insurance is a
very important
thing, just after setting aside money for it.
We should set aside money for investments and our celebrations. Otherwise, we may
lose everything we have earned in a moment. However, if we are firmly convinced that we cannot afford this much money, then we should
take it even if the premium is low or the coverage is low.  Having something is
better than nothing.
Next, the most important thing to have in a good health insurance
policy
is the restoration
benefit.  This can be done in many ways.
However, to put it simply, we can assume that we have taken out coverage worth a few
lakhs for our family
.
Someone got sick. That lakh
or a lakh rupees was spent on
the hospital.  Even though it was complete, the insurance
company covered it.  It has
become a big profit for us.  But then what is
left is only three lakh rupees
.  The coverage for the rest of the family members for the entire year is
only Rs. 3 lakh.   If
someone falls ill during a difficult time, all
the money that comes out of this three lakh rupees will be lost from our hands.
So, it's
never good to come like that.
What can we do in the meantime?  Can I
take out a policy with a large coverage
?  That's not possible.  The premium will be
higher.  So what can be done
?  Take out a policy with restoration benefits
.  If that's the case, once a
hospital admission
costs this much money, that much money will be
restored.  That is, in the first
case, the coverage was Rs 10 lakh, but
Rs 7 lakh
was spent on a hospital admission.  However, this
Rs 7 lakh will be
refilled by the insurance company once the hospital admission is over
.  And if someone else
needs it, they
can get coverage for ten lakhs.  Therefore,
if you have a policy without a restoration benefit, it is currently mandatory to immediately port it and
transfer your policy to a company or plan that has a restoration benefit
.  Now, this restoration
benefit comes in many forms.  There is partial and there is
complete.  That means
we have a policy worth ten lakh rupees.   As
mentioned at the beginning, it costs one lakh rupees
.  So it's partially
gone, the money has gone.  Even though the ten lakh
rupees are complete, it is not over yet.  This partial restoration is the feature that refills the coverage of Rs. 10
lakh even if it is not exhausted
but there is Rs. 3 lakh remaining.
They will
restore, even if it is partial.  But if we
say that we will restore only when it is complete, then in the case we mentioned earlier, there is
now three lakh rupees
remaining in that policy.  So, if
the bill for the next hospital case is Rs. 1 lakh, the
insurance company will bear this Rs. 3 lakh
.  The next five
lakh rupees will be taken from us
.  Well, it's complete and
finished.  Then
refill this 10 lakhs only for the next hospital case
.  So,
even if we use it partially and fill it again, the
restore feature is the
best.  Should
you take it just because it says it has a restoration feature?  It should never be
taken.  The feature that it will be
restored even if it is used partially
is a good thing. Similarly, the
second thing is that if we have been
admitted again and again for the same diseases,
now we have a heart disease, and we
first spent Rs. 1 lakh for that heart disease, then we have Rs. 2 lakh left, and we are admitted again for a heart disease, and we have
spent Rs. 1 lakh again, and we have Rs. 2 lakh left, but it is for the
same disease, but we have been
admitted to the hospital again,
so we do not have to fill it again.
Now we see a benefit that no matter what disease it is, it will be
restored even if it is the same disease
.  This
second one is the best.  If there is a facility that allows partial and
repeated restoration no matter how many times you are admitted for any illness,
we should take a plan with such restoration benefits
.  Now,
when looking at a plan with a restoration benefit, if you see that the premium is
a little high, or even if it is
a little higher, it would be
beneficial for us to take it.  Because we are taking it for granted.  If we
don't have that much money in our hands or can't
afford it, should we
wait until we have the money?  Never wait for something to happen.
For now, at least
get a plan with basic features.
Having a plan is better than having nothing.
Next is Sublimit.  We go out of our way to
find a better plan, but the
sub-limit is what it says we will cover up to this amount for certain illnesses.
We have a policy with a coverage of Rs. 10 lakhs.  We bought it because it was cheap
.
So it must have said that if it's a kidney-
related illness,
we'll cover up to two lakh rupees.  So, since we
have a coverage of 10 lakhs, if we get a
bill of 10 lakhs, will the
company cover us? The company
has said that if it is a kidney disease,
we will cover only up to 2 lakhs. So, is it
better to take a low premium? Never. We should
check if there is a sublimit.
We
should make sure that there is no sublimit for any important diseases. If not, it does not matter even if it is a plan of 1 crore
because there will be a sublimit for each disease. It will be
at the time of the bill of 10 lakhs.
We
check whether there is a sublimit. All this is to check whether it is a
Koli or not. There is no complication. As
I said, if you
go to the link in the comment, there is a call back option.
Many times,
we get customer care support in Malayalam. At
this time,
I liked this policy. I can ask which
diseases have a sublimit in this.
So, I can
understand it properly. After that, the
policy document will be given to us. If we can
read it, we should
read it or have
someone who can read it read it to us and
understand it properly. The next
room is  Rent Limits:
It has been said many times about room rent limits. A policy without them is
best.  If we go to many hospitals, the charges are
higher than in resorts.
I have been fortunate enough to stay in hospitals where the hospital rent is around 8500 rupees per day.
So
why was I allowed to stay like that?
There was no room rent limit in my policy, so no matter how much money I
took for a room, the money wouldn't go out of my pocket
.  So I took the
most premium room there
.  I took a room with AC.
Even though we are sick in the hospital,
we can still stay in a clean room without any problems
.  So,
get a room with no room rent limit that way.
Now, whether the room rent limit is one percent or
2 percent,
we need to understand that this charge is proportional to
other treatments and all important
treatments. The
room rent limit is Rs. 5,000.   If I had
booked a room for ten thousand,
I would have booked 50 percent more
.  Then the insurance company will cover all my
treatments by 50%
.  So, if a
bill comes for 10 lakhs,
even if there is 10 lakhs of coverage, they will only give 5 lakhs
.  5 lakhs will be over.
Therefore, it is best and
mandatory to take out insurance from
insurance companies that do not have room rent limits
.  Another thing to
note is that the cost of treatment is increasing year by year, and
hospitals are increasing room rent charges
.  So, if
we take the 5,000 rupees,
we know that we might not even
get a ward.
Any policy that is cheap or low-cost is
enough for me.  If you feel like you only have that much
income, then the
shared ward option is
not an option.  The money for all that is very
low, but we will have to
live in the ward.  But one
advantage here is that if we go to the most premium
hospital and
use the shared ward, we will
have the facilities of the room.
There are some good wards.  So, if
we want something like that, we can stay in the ward at the most premium
hospital with the best
doctors treating us
.  So if you have a
little money, you
can select such features.  There's no need to read every single plan, including what I've just
said and what I'm going to say next
.  The last
part is that once we get to this part of the website,
we will see the filter option.
Once we select each item and apply, we will be shown
the plans of insurance companies that only include those selected items
.  If we want,
we can select it again and compile it
.  This means that we have the opportunity to easily find each plan and the
plans of 51 insurance partners
using the filter option that we need to read and use technology
.  The next thing to check is the
waiting period.  I have taken out an
insurance policy from an insurance company
.  I must have paid a ten or so
rupees for it
.
I'm going to need surgery next year.   It may
be related to a hernia.  But
when I went to claim, I
realized that since it was a hernia-related
surgery, there was a three-year
waiting period.  So I wo
n't get that money back.
Because the insurance company told us from the beginning that it would only be covered after three years, and
we
signed up for it.  And then it doesn't
matter if you go to court.   The
insurance company is not cheating us.   This is
how this plan is, so
you have to understand it.
What are the waiting periods for each illness?
Maybe we should think of him as a sick person at first
.  Maybe it's sugar, maybe it's
cholesterol.  It must have been clearly written that
we will only cover the illnesses associated with it after this amount of time.
We need to understand that and
take a policy.  For some people, the surgeon may have
told them to do it within six months
or after a year
.
What happens if such people run away, take out a policy and cheat the insurance company?
Naturally, the risk of an insurance company going
bankrupt is high.  When that
happens, many people like you and me will have
taken out a policy, thinking that it will be useful in case of some major illness without making any claims
.  So are we
all stupid?  Wouldn't it be easy if a few people could
easily cheat the company
?
Then this is a good thing.  Because
this is also important for the survival of the insurance company
.  This is why it is
said that if we take out health insurance while we are
healthy, before we get sick, the
waiting period will
have passed by the time we and our family get sick later.  A
standard waiting period is that if
we are
admitted to the hospital for something other than an accident, such as a fever, there
will be a 30-day waiting period for all of that.  Because if
we get a fever before admission, we're
almost ready to be admitted
.  Then you can take out insurance
.  Then, if you go to a hospital and get a
bill of 10,000 or 50,000, it's a
big loss for the insurance company.
Therefore, there
will be a standard waiting period of 30 days.
In addition, there will be pre-existing
diseases.  It
could be sugar, it could be cholesterol, or some other
disease
.  If we
have not disclosed this, it
does not apply to us.  That means even the waiting period does not
apply.  Because
we
took out insurance by cheating the company.  Then
they can reject the claim at any time
.  So if you are sick, let's
say it clearly.  If we
say that, when the waiting period is
over, we will get treatment for the treatments related to that disease, but if we
don't say that, we will not get treatment for
other treatments related to that disease.
Then there is another thing.
Riders can be added for diseases like diabetes or BP,
that is, we can add extra features. The waiting period may be
reduced to
three years. There may
be a waiting period, but if you
pay a little more premium, there
are features that can be reduced to one year or two years.
After going to this filter section, it is natural to ask whether the waiting period for pre-existing diseases should be
reduced. If you
say reduce, the risk outside the company
increases, so keep in
mind that there is a possibility of a difference in the premium. If you have
the money, it is better to take the one with the best
features and the shortest waiting
period.
Now, when
taking a policy for a family
or a policy for women,  Even if you are
pregnant at the time of taking out the
policy, it is a great benefit for us if we make sure that we have
maternity coverage when we take out the policy.
Some companies offer a fixed benefit of Rs. 100,000
after paying the premium for three years together. That too with a waiting period of just
three months. If we look at it, we usually get coverage for maternity related matters for one year or two years. On the other hand, if we say that the waiting period is only three months,
even those who are pregnant up to six months can join this policy.
Not only that,
the company also bears the pregnancy expenses of Rs. 100,000.
When we take out these three years together, the
premium is often close to Rs. 100,000 or a little more than that.
However, one thing we need to think about is that
we are taking a health insurance with a coverage of Rs. 10 lakhs, 15 lakhs, and 20 lakhs.
Instead of paying Rs. 100,000 to the hospital, wouldn't we get
health
insurance coverage for three years almost free for us and our family?
This is a big benefit for us.
Please do not take out insurance until the last minute, i.e., the fifth and sixth months.   If
you take that approach, the places available are very
few.  This platform I provided is the
only one where you can see plans with a three-month waiting period
.
Some companies
offer policies that are exclusive to the location where many policies are sold together.  That's how it was seen.
But if the baby is born a little early, you may not
get the three-month waiting period,
so don't wait until the last minute to get it
.  Let's assume that we have maternity coverage for a year, two or three
years in advance and that
the child has Day One coverage
.
Why Day One coverage for a child?  If a child is
born a little early,
they will have to be kept in the NICU. There are
children who are born every four or five months.  There are many cases where the cost of such children is between
30 lakhs and 40 lakhs
.
There will be cases that you know firsthand.
There is also a case I know of.  So, if you
ask me for such a huge amount, is it unlikely that
any parent would be willing to give up their child?
Or is it unlikely that they would have to sell everything they have
.  So, if we want our child to have
coverage from day one,
we should take out a plan a few years in advance.
The child will only
get Day One coverage if we join the plan at least nine months in advance.  So, in
my opinion, each delivery
is a risk of Rs 50 lakh.  Should
we take a risk of Rs 50 lakhs and
stand for it? Wouldn't it be better if we
take out health insurance in advance to cover the child?
Moreover, even if the child
is born normally, if there is some
problem that is not found in the scan, the
insurance companies will never bear the costs of the child's treatment because
most insurances have
provisions to add the child after three months. So, if the
child has some problem,
the company may not be ready to add the child after three months. Now, if the child is
added, they
will ask for a high premium.  But when the child
is born, that child does not exist
.  If
we secure that child's insurance coverage beforehand,
we will have many
benefits.  Insurance is always meant to cover risks so that no one has to face any problems.
We
should never use it.  But
this creates a situation where you can go to sleep with peace of mind.
Set aside a little money.  Although there are plans that provide
coverage of up to one crore if you set aside 300 or 400 rupees, if
we spend a little more money, if we are a 20-year-old
person, a plan of 12,000 rupees, if we are a
30-year-old person,
a plan of at least 30,000 rupees,
we can take a good plan that covers pretty much everything. The
next thing we need to
look at is whether it covers pre- and post-
hospitalization expenses. It is
good if it covers at least 60 days pre- and 60 days post-hospitalization
because there will be expenses not only in the hospital. If you also
cover other expenses related to the same treatment, the
hospital expenses may
be a small amount. After that, if the
company says that the expenses for all the treatments related to the same disease that come after will be borne by the company,
we
can save a little more money.
Another thing to note is that there are people who become bedridden.
When their parents get old, they may not
need hospital admission.
The doctor may have told them that they can be looked after from home.
When such a situation arises,
Check if there are domiciliary care treatments,
that is, they said that the best policies change with age. If
we are young, we will not
need such a policy clause. But if we
make sure that this is also there when we get a little older, we will be a little safer
because more money may be
spent. It will not be a hospital admission. As
mentioned earlier, if you
take all this glucose from home and go to the doctor for
treatment from home, the
more expenses will be
incurred. If the company covers this,
why not?
Even if the premium may be a little higher, if we have this
clause, it will be very beneficial for us to save a lot of money. We have
understood all the important things we need in a policy,
understood all the important terms, selected all these and
found a policy of a good insurance company and when we
go to make the payment, we
ask whether we want a top up or a super top up. That is, we have taken
an insurance policy with a coverage of 10
lakhs. If we pay a small extra charge, we
can add a coverage of 20 lakhs as a top up along with the coverage of 10 lakhs.  You may be saying that
this top up has a
deductible,
that is, we take a policy of 10 lakhs and the
hospital
costs us 1 lakh rupees and the remaining 2 lakh
rupees. We have taken
a policy without restoration benefit,
so we have 2 lakh rupees
left. The next
hospital case comes up, where we
spend 3 lakh rupees or 2
lakh rupees in insurance,
so the insurance company will
bear the remaining 1 lakh rupees.
We think that this top up policy will
cover the 20 lakhs,
but the top up policies must have
clearly stated that the
deductible is 1 lakh rupees or 4
lakh rupees, that is, if
your normal insurance bill exceeds 1 lakh rupees,
we will cover things that are not covered
or we will cover the amount outside of it.
Secondly, these top up policies cover only if the bill we get is
more than 3 lakh rupees or
more than 1 lakh rupees.
So the 1
lakh rupees will be taken out of our hands.
Now,
super top up policies are a solution to this.  Yes,
even if you have to pay a little more than the top-up policies, the
above problem does not arise
because the first hospital case we mentioned above
cost Rs. 1 lakh and the
second hospital case
cost Rs. 3 lakh, which is a total of Rs. 11 lakh.
This is considered the total bill,
meaning
they have spent more than the deductible of Rs. 1 lakh.
Therefore,
these super top-up policies cover the second cost of Rs. 2 lakh plus Rs. 1 lakh.
So, the best thing to do is to take
super top-up policies, but
we do not need top-up and super top-up
because we
take policies with restoration benefit. When that happens,
naturally,
these
restoration benefit
policies can cover a lot more. So,
try to take the one with restoration benefit. If you
have not taken it yet, you should
take the super top-up. If such policies seem expensive and expensive, if you
have money,
take it anyway.  If that doesn't work, don't
go for top-up. Just
take out the super top-up. The
next thing we need to check is whether
our policy has a day care feature
.  If we talk about this day care treatment, all
our
treatments are very advanced now.
Because of these advanced treatments, many surgeries can be
performed without admission. Now, if the
treatments are related to hernia or appendicitis, they do not
require admission. The
person is sent home after the operation in one, two, three or four hours. At this
time, whether we are admitted or
not, the
insurance coverage must have been stated at the time of admission. If
we have taken such an insurance in the policy documents, if there is no day care,
we will not
get money for that treatment.  But we have undergone a major
surgery that has
cost millions.  If there is a day care center at this time, if we
inform the insurance company in advance that we have received such a treatment or that the doctor has said something like this, and if it is a
hospital that offers cashless treatment, we can have the treatment covered in
full by the
insurance company and be
discharged without having to pay a single penny.   I
wonder if there will be a situation where you won't have to pay a single rupee while saying this?  There are cases where you don't have to pay a single rupee
.  There are also cases where a small amount of money is often lost, ranging from 10 to
15%, meaning up to Rs 30,000 for a bill of Rs 2 lakh
.  Why is
this happening?  This is where
we need
to check if consumables are covered.  That is,
when we perform an operation,
there will be doctor's gloves, syringes, needles, cotton, the
doctor's gown, all these
things are single-use, they can be
used only once. The
insurance company must
have said in advance that we will not cover such things. So, if a
surgery costs one lakh rupees, it may be for things like
medicines, etc. At
this time, we all
have a policy of ten lakhs, but we
only get one lakh rupees for treatment. At
this time,
when we spend 15,000 rupees, people
often create problems. The
insurance company says this and that, and then says, "I am fine," and then takes
money from us. Is it really what the
insurance company said, "I am fine," and it has already
said from the beginning that consumables are not covered. No
one who took this policy
knows what consumables are, and they do not know that they should tell the person who gave them that. This is where the
confusion comes in.
Take care to take a policy that covers all important consumables. Even if all consumables may not be
covered,
take policies that cover at least 90 percent of everything. Consumables are
very important. If it is a
big bill, say 15 percent, then if it is a bill of
one lakh and 10
lakhs, it will be one
lakh and one and a half lakhs.
So we need to pay attention to this too. Even if it is
mandatory, we must take it. We must
understand what features we need. We must understand that it is not
good for everyone to have the same insurance company.
We must understand what
features we need in the best insurance.
After that, apply filters and
re-purchase and
read it carefully. If not, request a call back and
find a good policy. We can take a policy and
take it in EMI as well. If you want, you can pay the
full payment and
take it. The
important thing we need to pay attention to here is that if there are elderly people
at home, even if it is mandatory,
they should take health insurance for them.
It should be a minimum of 15 lakhs or 20 lakhs.
Plans with coverage are the best. If you
don't have that much money in your hand, or if you have
less,
take an insurance plan that is less expensive. It's
not enough for us alone.
We make sure that we cover all those who are close to us, such as our dependent children or our spouse. After doing all this, what will we do when
we get a good insurance
policy and claim?
What if we have any doubts? Because we have taken up to 25 percent
online discount. These
companies do not need to run an office for this. They do not
need to pay its current bill. They do not need to have
staff there.
That is why we get such a low
premium from the best company offline. It is also possible to
take the same plan online.
But when you
think about what to do when a claim comes,
people who have claimed insurance at least once know that here, especially the
agent or intermediary has
no role. It is the
hospitals that talk to the insurance company. Especially
when we go to the network hospital, if we submit photostatic copies of our insurance card
or related documents,
our PAN card, our Aadhaar card,
etc.,
that will be the
claim.  If you have any doubts, the
insurance
help desks in hospitals will help you.
Now, whether it is the company whose
insurance you have taken, there will be a toll-free
number that you can call and
seek help. Now, if you take
an insurance through the link that I have given in the comment box and description box, you will also get
24/30 minutes of claim support from that platform.
So, if you need a claim,
we can seek three types of help. Now, no matter whose
help we have, we can get the policy
document through this. It will be sent to our
home after a week.
Read this policy document carefully. It is
good for us if we understand in advance what things we will and will not get a claim for. It is not enough if we understand it only.
Tell our life partner and the people who are close to us about the conditions of this policy.
Because if
any accident happens to us,
they are the ones who have to claim. So, keep one more
thing in mind here.
Whatever the case, there are
a lot of medical expenses, aren't they?
It is increasing at a high
rate.
Inflation in India, when we say
inflation in the health sector, has reached
14 percent. At this time,
we will not be able to cover this with our income,
with the big money in our bank, or
with our investments.
Even if we can cover this, we will have to save a
little money and
secure that money.
So it is not a question of whether someone wants insurance or
not. We have learned today how to find the best company and the
best plan. Don't
put it off for tomorrow. We need to take
a good plan today. We need to take this health insurance, we need the
people who are close to us. We need to
share this video with our friends.
Then
after taking this health insurance, if we
file taxes under the old tax regime,
we have the opportunity to get
tax benefits of up to Rs. 75,000 under 80D. If
you check the link I gave, you will
see an online discount of up to 25 percent. In addition, expatriates do not have to
pay 18% GST.
Expatriates should pay attention to savings in the country.
We
all know that it is wrong to even open such accounts. Therefore, try to get a policy by sending
money only through NRE accounts. If
that is the case, the 18 percent GST will come
back to us.
I firmly believe that everyone has understood what I have said today. It is
not complicated and anyone can open their own account.
So just start and
read all the things.
The link and everything you need for that
is in the comment box and description box.  If you still have doubts,
there is also the option to request a call back.  So please share this
video with as many people as possible
.  Anyway, let's
meet again with another good topic.  It's Me Anurag Signing
Off